Guide to the Arielle Greenberg Zine Collection, 1973-1995, bulk 1993-1995 RL.00477
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Arielle Greenberg Zine collection
1973-1995 bulk 1993-1995
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Greenberg, Arielle (collector)
RL.00477
5.4 Linear Feet
Arielle Greenberg is a poet, editor, and assistant professor in the English department at Columbia College, Chicago, Ill. This collection consists of 367 zines dated from 1973 to 1995, likely collected by the donor from 1992-1995. The collection primarily includes personal zines by women (though some are by men) that focus on the riot grrrl scene, feminism, punk music, and progressive political causes. Many of the zines include correspondence from the authors. The collection also includes personal correspondence and correspondence from zine authors between 1987 and 1995, with the bulk dating from 1993 to 1995.
3,375 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Arielle Greenberg Zine Collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2005.
Biographical Note
Arielle Greenberg is a poet, editor, writer, and assistant professor in the English department at Columbia College, Chicago, Ill. She is the author of the poetry collections My Kafka Century (Action Books, 2005) and Given (Verse, 2002) and the chapbooks Shake Her (Dusie Kollektiv, 2009) and Farther Down: Songs from the Allergy Trials (New Michigan, 2003). Her poems have been included the 2004 and 2005 editions of Best American Poetry and a number of other anthologies, including Legitimate Dangers (Sarabande, 2006), and she is the recipient of a MacDowell Colony fellowship and other awards. A translated volume of her selected poetry is out in German from LuxBooks. She authored the zine "William Wants a Doll" beginning in 1993.
Collection Overview
This collection consists of 367 zines dated from 1973 to 1995, likely collected by the donor from 1992-1995. The collection primarily includes personal zines by women (though some are by men) that focus on the riot grrrl scene, feminism, punk music, and progressive political causes. Many of the zines include correspondence from the authors. The collection also includes personal correspondence and correspondence from zine authors between 1987 and 1995, with the bulk dating from 1993 to 1995. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Related Material
Sarah Dyer Zine Collection
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture, Duke University
Bingham Center Women’s Zine Collection
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture, Duke University
Dwayne Dixon Zine Collection
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture, Duke University
Amy Mariaskin Zine Collection
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture, Duke University
Ailecia Ruscin Zine Collection
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture, Duke University
Sarah Wood Zine Collection
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture, Duke University
Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Zines -- United States -- Periodicals; Riot grrrl movement; Self-publishing; Women -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Underground press publications -- United States; Young women -- United States -- Social life and customs; Comic books, strips, etc.; Feminism -- United States; Greenberg, Arielle (collector); Greenberg, Arielle (collector); Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Personal Papers Series, 1987-1995, 2 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Series includes personal correspondence and correspondence from zine authors.
  - Correspondence: Letters, 1987-1995 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Letters, 1995 and undated (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Postcards, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - Loose Items and clippings (Box 2)
  - Mailing Lists (Box 2)
- Zines Series, 1973-1995, 5 boxes
  This series consists of 367 zines dating from 1973 to 1995, likely collected by the donor from 1992 to 1995. The collection primarily includes personal zines by women (though some are by men) that focus on the riot grrrl scene, feminism, punk music, and progressive political causes. Many of the zines include correspondence from the authors.
  - Absolute Beginners (Box 3)
  - Absolute Beginners Club Social Handbook (Box 3)
  - Action Girl Newsletter, 2 issues (Box 3)
  - Aim Your Dick (Box 3)
  - Animal Review (Box 3)
  - Another Pair of Shoes, 2 issues (Box 3)
  - Armadillo Culture, 2 issues (Box 3)
  - Asian Girls are Rad, 2 issues (Box 3)
  - Astro Delight (Box 3)
  - Attagirl (Box 3)
  - Baby Doll (Box 3)
  - Bamboo Girl (Box 3)
  - BananaFish (Box 3)
  - Bi Girl World!, 3 issues (Box 3)
  - Big Nurse Skateboarding Magazine (Box 3)
  - Blaster! (Box 3)
  - Boise State University Publications Catalog (Box 3)
  - Booby Guts (Box 3)
  - Book Your Own Fuckin' Life (Box 3)
  - Bovine Gazette (Box 3)
  - Box Dog Cher Doll Catalog (Box 3)
  - Box of 64, 4 issues (Box 3)
  - The Boycott Quarterly (Box 3)
  - Broom (Box 3)
  - Brown Star (Box 3)
  - Bruce on a Stick (Box 3)
  - Bubba's Live Bait (Box 3)
  - Bulldozer (Box 3)
  - Bust, 5 issues (Box 3)
  - Busty Bea's Bush (Box 3)
  - The Cackler (Box 4)
  - Cake (Box 4)
  - Cake (Box 4)
  - Cannibal Porn (Box 4)
  - Cashiers du Cinemart (Box 4)
  - Caught in Flux, 2 issues (Box 4)
  - Celtic Pamplemousse, 2 issues (Box 4)
  - Cheese Log (Box 4)
  - Chickfactor, 7 issues (Box 4)
  - Chick Publications, 3 issues (Box 4)
  - Combat (Box 4)
  - Continental Restyling, 2 issues (Box 4)
  - Crystal Blue Persuasion (Box 4)
  - Cupsize, 2 issues (Box 4)
  - Daggy Madeline (Box 4)
  - Dark (Box 4)
  - daS KApital (Box 4)
  - A Day in the Life Of…, 2 issues (Box 4)
  - Dead Jackie Susann Quarterly (Box 4)
  - Deal With It! (Box 4)
  - Die Evan Dando, Die (Box 4)
  - Die Right Now, 4 issues (Box 4)
  - Double Bill, 2 issues (Box 4)
  - Dream Scene Magazine, 2 issues (Box 4)
  - Dumb Things, 2 issues (Box 4)
  - The Duplex Planet (Box 4)
  - Edna's Edibles (Box 4)
  - An Eency-Weenie Travel Journal (Box 4)
  - Ethel (Box 4)
  - Euphoria (Box 4)
  - Everything Tastes Better With Ketchup, 2 issues (Box 4)
  - Exhaust Monthly (Box 4)
  - Factsheet Five, 7 issues (Box 5)
  - Feeding the Fowls, 5 issues (Box 5)
  - Femcore (Box 5)
  - Feminist Baseball, 2 issues (Box 5)
  - Fern, 2 issues (Box 5)
  - FFA (Box 5)
  - FFA & My Bloody Uterus (Box 5)
  - Film Canon, 4 issues (Box 5)
  - Final Solution (Box 5)
  - Firefly, 2 issues (Box 5)
  - Firefly (Box 5)
  - Flatter, 5 issues (Box 5)
  - The Flying Bitch Sisters Present, 3 issues (Box 5)
  - Foxy (Box 5)
  - Frisco Piss Co, 2 issues (Box 5)
  - Frog Prince (Box 5)
  - Fuel (Box 5)
  - Function, 3 issues (Box 5)
  - Garbles, 4 issues (Box 6)
  - Gecko, 2 issues (Box 6)
  - Get Off My Property (Box 6)
  - Ginger's Rag, 2 issues (Box 6)
  - Girl Fiend, 2 issues (Box 6)
  - Girl Frenzy, 2 issues (Box 6)
  - Global Mail (Box 6)
  - Gogglebox (Box 6)
  - Go Metric (Box 6)
  - Greedy Bastard (Box 6)
  - The Guy Forward Hour (Box 6)
  - Half-Life (Box 6)
  - Harpies & Quines (Box 6)
  - Hello Kitty Gazette (Box 6)
  - Hey There, Barbie Girl! (Box 6)
  - Highest Population of Rock Stars (Box 6)
  - Hip Clown Rag, 3 issues (Box 6)
  - Hmmm…, 3 issues (Box 6)
  - Holy Titclamps, 3 issues (Box 6)
  - Hourglass (Box 6)
  - Hysteria (Box 6)
  - I Hate Brenda (Box 6)
  - I'm So Fucking Beautiful (Box 6)
  - Interesting (Box 6)
  - Jail Bait, 2 issues (Box 6)
  - The J. Cruelty Catalog (Box 6)
  - Jelly Bean, 2 issues (Box 6)
  - Joe Blow Godot (Box 6)
  - Johnny on the Spot (Box 6)
  - Jumbo Shrimp (Box 6)
  - Jungle Gym (Box 6)
  - Just Like a Girl (Box 6)
  - Ka-Blam!, 2 issues (Box 6)
  - Karma Lapel, 2 issues (Box 6)
  - Kelp, 3 issues (Box 6)
  - Kiki Zine (Box 6)
  - Kitschy Kitschy Coup, 3 issues (Box 6)
  - Kitten Kore (Box 6)
  - Kitty (Box 6)
  - The Latest News (Box 7)
  - Libel, 2 issues (Box 7)
  - Lizard Music (Box 7)
  - Loud as Hell (Box 7)
  - Lusy's Angry (Box 7)
  - Mad Planet, 2 issues (Box 7)
  - Maximumrocknroll (Box 7)
  - Mazel-Tov Cocktail (Jew-Core) (Box 7)
  - Meniscus (Box 7)
  - The Michael Ellis Chronicles (Box 7)
  - Mischa (Box 7)
  - Mister Rogers' Neighborhood (Box 7)
  - Moe Magazine, 2 issues (Box 7)
  - Ms. America (Box 7)
  - Muffin Bones (Box 7)
  - Mystery Date (Box 7)
  - Mystery Science Manifesto 3000, 4 issues (Box 7)
  - No Pop Heroes (Box 7)
  - Off My Jammy (Box 7)
  - Oompa! Oompa! (Box 7)
  - Oya (Box 7)
  - Paintspot (Box 7)
  - Panophobia, 2 issues (Box 7)
  - Pawholes, 2 issues (Box 7)
  - Peech Fuzz (Box 7)
  - Pesky Meddling Girls, 2 issues (Box 7)
  - Picnic (Box 7)
  - Pixie Girl, 3 issues (Box 7)
  - Plaintive Wombat Gazette (Box 7)
  - Planet Girl (Box 7)
  - Plotz, 2 issues (Box 7)
  - Plume, 2 issues (Box 7)
  - Queen Itchie (Box 8)
  - Queer (Box 8)
  - Queer Zine Explosion (Box 8)
  - R2-D2 is an Indie Rocker (Box 8)
  - Rampaging Teenage Pervert (Box 8)
  - Rantcycle (Box 8)
  - Rats Live on No Evil Star, 2 issues (Box 8)
  - Reality Check (Box 8)
  - Rediscoveries Newsletter (Box 8)
  - Reggae Chicken (Box 8)
  - Revels and Revolts (Box 8)
  - Riot Grrrl (Box 8)
  - Roadside (Box 8)
  - Rollerderby (Box 8)
  - Roulez, 6 issues (Box 8)
  - Ruckus (Box 8)
  - Rumpus Room, 2 issues (Box 8)
  - Runt (Box 8)
  - Scam (Box 8)
  - The Scaredy-Cat Stalker (Box 8)
  - Scootering International (Box 8)
  - Scram (Box 8)
  - Second Guess (Box 8)
  - Septophilia Records, 2 issues (Box 8)
  - Shattered Mind (Box 8)
  - Shit and Garbage, 3 issues (Box 8)
  - Skankina (Box 8)
  - Slug & Lettuce (Box 8)
  - Slut Monkey (Box 8)
  - Smart Like Eve (Box 8)
  - The Snopeses Go Camping, 2 issues (Box 8)
  - Snow Day Hoax (Box 8)
  - Sourpuss, 4 issues (Box 8)
  - Space Girls (Box 8)
  - Sparkly Kitty Stickers, 3 issues (Box 8)
  - Spawn of Satan (Box 8)
  - Speak for Yourself (Box 8)
  - Splashdown (Box 8)
  - Squareone (Box 8)
  - Squeaky Debris (Box 8)
  - Stardrift (Box 8)
  - Stinkzine, 2 issues (Box 8)
  - Stuff by Me, 3 issues (Box 8)
  - Sugar and Spice (Box 8)
  - Sunny Sundae Smile (Box 8)
  - Super Girl (Box 8)
  - Super Keen (Box 8)
  - Tabula Rasa, 2 issues (Box 9)
  - Teenage Gang Debs, 2 issues (Box 9)
  - Teen Fag, 2 issues (Box 9)
  - Ten Thousand Thinks (Things), 2 issues (Box 9)
  - That Girl, 3 issues (Box 9)
  - This Is A Test (Box 9)
  - Thrift Score (Box 9)
  - Thrill, 7 issues (Box 9)
  - Turtle Wax (Box 9)
  - Twenty Bus (Box 9)
  - Ulysses (Box 9)
  - Unclean (Box 9)
  - Underdog (Box 9)
  - Underground Means and Technology (Box 9)
  - Untitled (Box 9)
  - Velvet Glove (Box 9)
  - Velvet Grass (Box 9)
  - Verboslammed (Box 9)
  - Vespa (Box 9)
  - Violation Fez (Box 9)
  - Violet Awkward (Box 9)
  - Vivid (Box 9)
  - WAAAAAAAAAH! (Box 9)
  - The Web, 5 issues (Box 9)
  - When She Was Good, 3 issues (Box 9)
  - Wick, 2 issues (Box 9)
  - Wiglet (Box 9)
  - Wild Honey Pie (Box 9)
  - William Wants a Doll, 4 issues (Box 9)
  - Withering Snout (Box 9)
  - Words and Smiles (Box 9)
  - Wow Cool (Box 9)
  - Xenon (Box 9)
  - X Magazine (Box 9)
  - The Yo La Tengo Gazette (Box 9)
  - Zum (Box 9)